Finding Aid for BMC Media Services records, 1851-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Topical Files
  - Non-Medical Related Topical Files
    - Executive Education
      - Workshops, 1997; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Fellowship Recruiting (Barbour Scholars), 1999 (Box 28)
    - Flying Aces Professional Frisby[sic] Team, 2001 (Box 28)
    - Housekeeping, 1991 (Box 28)
    - Housing
      - Bio Class Lab, 2001 (Box 28)
      - Brochure
        - 1992 (Box 28)
        - (Re-shoot of Custodian), 1992 (Box 28)
        - (M.L. King Day Brochure), 1993 (Box 28)
        - 1996 (Box 28)
      - Check Presentation, 1996; 2 folders (Box 28)
      - Environment Community Service, 2001 (Box 28)
      - Focus on Community Service, 2001 (Box 28)
      - Hillel Ad, 1996 (Box 28)
      - Honor Students in Quad/Round Table Discussion/Housing Information, 2001 (Box 28)
      - Karaoke at Couzens Hall, 2001 (Box 28)
      - Mentorship Group, 2001 (Box 28)
      - Ritter Housing, 1994; 2 folders (Box 28)
      - UROP Animation of Mastodons, 2001 (Box 28)
      - Women's Stories of Health, Illness and Healing, 2000 (Box 28)
    - Human Resources and Development
      - Advanced Customer Service, 1999 (Box 28)
      - Basic Management Class, 1995 (Box 28)
      - Behaviorally Based Interviewing, 1997 (Box 28)
      - Concepts and Practices Workshops, 1996 (Box 28)
      - Franklin Planning Seminar, 1995 (Box 28)
      - Interiors of New Facility, 1998 (Box 28)
      - Listening, 1999 (Box 28)
      - Michigan Manufacturing Technology Center (MMTC) Move, 2001 (Box 28)
      - Minority Committee Meeting, 1992 (Box 28)
      - Myers and Briggs Type Indicator Workshop, 1996 (Box 28)
      - Performance Coaching for Managers, 1997 (Box 28)
      - Planning for Retirement, 1996 (Box 28)
      - Process Mapping, 1996 (Box 28)
      - Project Management Class, 1996 (Box 28)
      - Staff Photos, 1997 (Box 28)
      - Sue McMahon, 1996 (Box 28)
      - Team Leader Training, 1997 (Box 28)
      - Team-Leader, 1997 (Box 28)
      - Writing it Right, 1998 (Box 28)
    - Industrial and Operations Engineering, 1996 (Box 28)
    - Information, School of
      - Robert Warner Retirement, 1996 (Box 28)
    - Institute for Social Research (ISR)
      - Computer Training, 1992 (Box 28)
      - ISR/RCGD (Research Center for Group Dynamics) Situations and Portraits, 2001 (Box 28)
    - International Institute
      - Calligraphy Reception, 2001 (Box 28)
      - Center for Japanese Studies, 2001 (Box 28)
      - Japanese Discussion Panel, 2001 (Box 28)
    - INS/MIS (Medical Information Systems?)
      - Annual Report, 1993; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - ITI (?), 1997 (Box 28)
    - Japanese Studies
      - Toyota Professorship, 2001 (Box 28)
    - Kinesiology
      - Down Center -- Ulrich, 2001 (Box 28)
      - Mobility Lab, 2001 (Box 28)
    - Law School, 1999 (Box 28)
    - Learning Resource Center
      - Patient Group, 2000 (Box 28)
      - STD Interview, 1999 (Box 28)
      - SPP Brochure, 2000 (Box 28)
      - Male Patients for Medical School, 2000 (Box 28)
    - Library Development
      - Donors Brochure, 2000 (Box 28)
      - Hermelin Endowment, 1997 (Box 28)
    - Library Public Relations, 1998 (Box 28)
    - Library, University
      - Knowledge Navigation Center, 1997 (Box 28)
    - (LSA) College of Literature, Science and the Arts Development (Box 29)
      - Goldenberg reception, undated (Box 29)
      - Goldenberg/Awards, undated (Box 29)
      - H.S. Students in Classroom and Computer Lab, 2000 (Box 29)
      - Laurie Luncheon, 2000 (Box 29)
      - Math Scholars Camp, 2000 (Box 29)
      - Moscow Prize Awards
        - 2000 (Box 29)
        - undated (Box 29)
    - Lynn Limited, 1995; 1996 (Box 29)
    - M-Line, 1989 (Box 29)
    - M-Link, 1994 (Box 29)
    - M-Works, 1998 (Box 29)
    - Martha Cook Building, 1997 (Box 29)
    - Material Management
      - Equipment/Studio, 1996 (Box 29)
      - Group Shot, 1987 (Box 29)
      - Portraits, 1990 (Box 29)
    - Mechanical Engineering, 2001 (Box 29)
    - Michigan Journalism Fellows
      - Hovey Lecture, 2001 (Box 29)
      - President Duderstadt, undated (Box 29)
    - Michigan Solar Car, 1992 (Box 29)
    - MMTC (Michigan Manufacturing and Technology Center?)
      - Board of Directors, 1998 (Box 29)
      - Group of 80, 1998 (Box 29)
      - Staff Portraits
        - 1998 (Box 29)
        - 1999 (Box 29)
    - Minority Engineering Program
      - Group Portraits, 1989 (Box 29)
      - Retention Seminar, 1998 (Box 29)
    - Minority Student Affairs
      - Brochure Photos and Group Shot, 1992 (Box 29)
      - Group Shot, 1989 (Box 29)
      - Minority Student Affairs, 1990 (Box 29)
    - Music, School of
      - Judith Becker Symposium, 2001 (Box 29)
    - Natural Resources, School of, 1995 (Box 29)
    - Occupational Safety and Environmental Health
      - M-Quality Expo, 1996 (Box 29)
      - Safety Poster, 1999 (Box 29)
    - Parking Maintenance, 1996 (Box 29)
    - Parking Services, 1995 (Box 29)
    - Personal, 1996; undated
      - Dr. Weiner and Family, 1996 (Box 29)
      - Figueroa Family, 1998 (Box 29)
    - Printing Services, 1996 (Box 29)
    - Public Health, School of
      - Alumni Board Reception, 1998 (Box 29)
      - Alumni Faculty Day, 1996 (Box 29)
      - Bernstein Lecture, 1999 (Box 29)
      - Blackerby Lecture, 1999 (Box 29)
      - Boehnke and Lange, 1997] (Box 29)
      - Brian Hubbard and John Williams, 1999 (Box 29)
      - Brochures, 1997 (Box 29)
      - Career Fair, 1997 (Box 29)
      - Carol Weissman and Student, 1998 (Box 29)
      - Community Fair, 1998 (Box 29)
      - Connell and Group, 1997 (Box 29)
      - Convocation Kick-Off, 1999 (Box 29)
      - Convocation
        - 1998 (Box 29)
        - 1999 (Box 29)
      - Dean with Surgeon General, 1997 (Box 29)
      - Dr. Hammond, 1997 (Box 29)
      - Dr. Lichenstein and Students, undated (Box 29)
      - Dr. Osborn/Students and Presentation, 1999 (Box 29)
      - Dr. Schottenfeld Group, 1996 (Box 29)
      - Emeritus Luncheon
        - 1997 (Box 29)
        - (Lecture Hall, Kiosk), 1998 (Box 29)
        - 1999 (Box 29)
      - Findings Magazine
        - Clean Lab, 1993 (Box 29)
        - Aug/Sept, 1994 (Box 29)
      - Genome Dialogue Groups, 1997 (Box 29)
      - Health Fair, 1996 (Box 29)
      - Health of our Children, 1998 (Box 29)
      - Held and Wolf, 1996 (Box 29)
      - Ice Cream Social, 1998 (Box 29)
      - John Snow Inc. (JSI) Lecture, 1997 (Box 29)
      - Loch-Caruso, Harris, Filbert, 1996 (Box 29)
      - Meschnick, Lange, Little, 1996 (Box 29)
      - Noreen Clark, Lise Anderson, Monique Green, 1998 (Box 29)
      - Orientation
        - (Fair), 1996 (Box 29)
        - (Picnic), 1997 (Box 29)
        - 1998 (Box 29)
      - Outreach for Asthma Research, 1998 (Box 29)
      - Parker and Janz, 1996 (Box 29)
      - Pfizer Donors, 1998 (Box 29)
      - Pfizer Lecture, 1999 (Box 29)
      - Population Fellows
        - Denning, V., Broderick, M., and Van Lith, L., 1999 (Box 29)
        - Heather Story and Meline Bode, 2000 (Box 29)
        - Hubert, Obenson, Decker, Keener, 2000 (Box 29)
        - Jenny Erickson, Loreli Goodyea, Denise Roth, 1999 (Box 29)
        - Nan Lewicky and Jennifer Wesson, 1999 (Box 29)
        - Patten, Laying, Mueller, Vohman, 2000 (Box 29)
        - Shelly Nicholson, 1999 (Box 29)
        - Sora Holtz, Elaine Roman, Karen Schmidt, Marya Plotkin, Ijeoma Agulefo, 2000 (Box 29)
      - Richardson/Dow Dinner, 1999 (Box 29)
      - Roloff and Hurwitz for Findings, 1998 (Box 29)
      - Salk Lab, Epid. Poster, Lib. Med. Center, Phone, 1996 (Box 29)
      - Salk Polio Vaccine Stamp Unveiling, 1999 (Box 29)
      - Senator Wheeler and Jobs Fair, 1997 (Box 29)
      - Speaker, 1997 (Box 29)
      - Student Pledge Program, 1997 (Box 29)
      - Students with Award, 1999 (Box 29)
      - Taylor, Jacobson, Tavas, Zellers, Banaszak-Holl, Mechnick, Warner and Vincent, 1999 (Box 29)
    - Public Policy, School of
      - (Grad. Group), 1998 (Box 29)
      - (Students), 1998 (Box 29)
      - 2000 (Grad. Class 2000 (Box 29)
    - Rackham Graduate School
      - Asian Women Scholars, 2000 (Box 29)
      - Barbour Scholars
        - 1995 (Box 29)
        - 1996 (Box 29)
        - 1997 (Box 29)
        - (Reception), 2001 (Box 29)
      - Dr. Coucouvanis, 1997 (Box 29)
      - Farewell to Dean J. D'Aimes, 1995 (Box 29)
      - Graduate Student Instructor (GSI) Awards
        - 1997 (Box 29)
        - 1998 (Box 29)
        - Braunschneider, Theresa, 1999 (Box 29)
        - Chai-Anant, Chayawadee, 2000 (Box 29)
        - Chutamanee, Onsuwan, 2000 (Box 29)
        - Cicciarelli, Louis, 2000 (Box 29)
        - Dombkowski, Kristen, 1999 (Box 29)
        - Haddad, Kristina, 1999 (Box 29)
        - Hall, Kim, 1999 (Box 29)
        - Jamal, Amaney, 1998 (Box 29)
        - Kinch, Ashby, 2000 (Box 29)
        - Kuxhausen, Anna, 1999 (Box 29)
        - Lacrosse, Stephanie and John Matsushima, 1998 (Box 29)
        - Mazie, Steven, 2000 (Box 29)
        - McGuire, Kristin, 2000 (Box 29)
        - Melitz, Marc, 1999 (Box 29)
        - Mertha, Andrew, 1999 (Box 29)
        - Moreau, Joe, 1999 (Box 29)
        - Nooruddin, Irfan, 2000 (Box 29)
        - O'Neal, Chris, 1998 (Box 29)
        - Palmgren, Glenn, 1999 (Box 29)
        - Parker, Karen, 1999 (Box 29)
        - Rogers, Douglas, 2000 (Box 30)
        - Schlossberg, Mark, 1999 (Box 30)
        - Schueller, Sheila, 1999 (Box 30)
        - Silbey, Chris, 1998 (Box 30)
        - Sinor, Jennifer, 1999 (Box 30)
        - Stanton, Nicole, 2000 (Box 30)
        - Steedman, Marek, 1999 (Box 30)
        - Vasquez-Kim, Pamela, 2000 (Box 30)
        - White, Laura, 2000 (Box 30)
        - Whitlow, William Lindsay, 2000 (Box 30)
        - Zimmerman, James, 1999 (Box 30)
      - Graduate Student Orientation, 1996 (Box 30)
      - Group Shots, 1998; 3 folders (Box 30)
      - Interim Dean Send-Off, 1996 (Box 30)
      - June Howard, 2000 (Box 30)
      - Lewis/Heidi Book Jacket, 2000 (Box 30)
      - Mark Broomfield -- Choreographer/Dancer, 1996 (Box 30)
      - Michigan Journalism Fellows, 2001; 2 folders (Box 30)
      - Moscow Scholars, 1998 (Box 30)
      - Mrs. [Margaret] Sokol and Students, 1996 (Box 30)
      - Portrait of Dean Nancy Cantor, 1996 (Box 30)
      - Portraits of Awards Recipients, 1995 (Box 30)
      - Post Doc Reception, 1998 (Box 30)
      - Pre Doc Dinner, 2001 (Box 30)
      - Pre Doc Reception, 1997 (Box 30)
      - Presentation of Certificate by Provost, 2000 (Box 30)
      - Rackham Faculty Group, 2000 (Box 30)
      - T.A. Awards
        - (Lunch/T.A. Awards Group), 1995 (Box 30)
        - 1996 (Box 30)
      - Wallenberg Letter Donation, 2000 (Box 30)
    - Services for Students with Disabilities
      - Adaptive Technology Lab, 2000 (Box 30)
      - Disabled student boarding van, 2000 (Box 30)
      - Fountain [by Michigan League]Brochure, 1993 (Box 30)
      - Student Handbook, 1993 (Box 30)
      - Students with Disabilities Brochure, 1993 (Box 30)
    - Social Work
      - Intern Portraits, 2000 (Box 30)
      - Interns, 1999 (Box 30)
      - Portraits, 1997 (Box 30)
      - [Portraits]10 Individual Shots, 2001 (Box 30)
      - Students, 2000 (Box 30)
    - Student Affairs, 1992; 1995
      - Dr. Kauffman's Retirement, undated (Box 30)
    - Technical Communications
      - Foreign Visitors Group, 1995 (Box 30)
      - Miki Restaurant, 1995 (Box 30)
    - Theatre
      - Ann Bogart Teaching, 1998 (Box 30)
      - Award Ceremony, 2000 (Box 30)
      - Bert Cardullo Book Signing, 1997 (Box 30)
      - Dramatic Writing Web Page, 1997 (Box 30)
      - Playwright and Director Speakers, 1998 (Box 30)
      - QTVR Panoramic of Mendelssohn Theatre (Box 30)
      - Scholarship Night
        - 1997 (Box 30)
        - 1998 (Box 30)
        - 1999 (Box 30)
    - Shadows for Graduate Brochure, 1996 (Box 30)
    - Sister Francesca Thompson, 1997 (Box 30)
    - Visiting Artist, 1998 (Box 30)
    - Web Page Project Candids, 1996 (Box 30)
  - Micsellanoues University Topics
    - University Administration, 1988 (Box 30)
    - University Development and Events
      - Faculty Awards Dinner, 2000 (Box 30)
      - Honorary Degree Reception, 2000 (Box 30)
      - Reception -- Ford, 2000 (Box 30)
    - Yearbook, undated (Box 30)
- Films
  The Films series consists of three outsize 16 mm films on four reels. Two of these were produced by or for UM Medical Television, and the other was produced for the Department of Prosthetics. See the contents list for additional information regarding each film.
  - Department of Prosthetics: (Box 31)
    - Fabrication of a Gel Socket, 16mm, undated (Box 31)
  - University of Michigan Medical Television
    - Dr. Child performing abdominal surgery [ca. 1970] (color; approx. 30 minutes; 16 mm; silent; identified on canister as "A Roll"). Summary: Footage of abdominal surgery. Film opens with brief shot of surgeon then proceeds with incision and surgical procedures. Exact type of operation unclear, perhaps kidney surgery. (Box 31)
    - Collis-Belsey [ca. 1960] (color; approx. 20 minutes on two reels; 16mm; silent). Summary: Lecture footage and demonstrations of procedures; exact subject of film uncertain. Unknown if finished print of film exists. (Box 31)
- Videotapes
  The Videotapes series (3 linear feet) consists of U-matic videotapes of the "Replacement Hospital Project" documenting construction of the "new" University Hospital and demolition of the "Old Main" Hospital. Cameras periodically captured footage of construction progress and related ceremonies. This footage was compiled for possible distillation into a final overview of the entire project. The bulk of the coverage is construction of the new hospital between 1981 and 1984. Tapes include the 1986 ceremonies dedicating the new University Hospital and Alfred A. Taubman Medical Center. The 1989 demolition of "Old Main" is also recorded. The videotaping captured various viewpoints giving an overall perspective, including slow pans. Frequently, the camera focused in on surrounding locations such as North Campus or traffic along Fuller Road. During ceremonies the cameras captured crowd views and officials. Although speeches were recorded on the videotape, most are inaudible.
  The videotapes contain valuable footage documenting the changing hospital landscape as well as important project officials. From a history of the construction industry perspective, the videotapes contain useful footage of the equipment and building construction methods employed in the early 1980s.
  - [Replacement Hospital (Taubman Center) Construction]
    - #1 (hillside, parking lot, hospital pans), 6/3/1981 (Box 32)
    - #2 (view of original site from Mott), 6/26/1981 (Box 32)
      (tape broken)
    - #3 (bulldozer razing building), 9/29/1981 (Box 32)
    - #4 (cranes demolishing building; railroad tracks; new hospital construction), 9/29/1981 (Box 32)
    - #5 (ground breaking ceremonies at hospital, speeches barely audible), 10/15/1981 (Box 32)
    - #6 (ground breaking ceremony, passing shovels), 10/15/1981 (Box 32)
    - #7 (view of site from southwest corner, crane digging), 12/21/1981 (Box 32)
    - #8 (construction of parking garage), 3/1/1982 (Box 32)
    - #9 (view from west, construction), 3/29/1982 (Box 32)
    - #10 (superstructure from top of Mott, construction, shot of Fuller Road), 5/12/1982 (Box 32)
    - #11 (view from MedSci I, workers on skeletal structure, cranes lifting beams), 8/10/1982 (Box 32)
    - #12 (ground level looking up at superstructure, riding crane ball), 10/15/1981 (Box 32)
    - #13 (partly finished exterior from south, worker on beams), 1/17/1983 (Box 32)
    - #14 (full building view from Fuller Road/Maiden Lane bridge, street level shot, traffic, building pan, crane turning), 1/27/1983 (Box 33)
    - #15 (crane lifting and workmen attaching exterior panels), 2/23/1983 (Box 33)
    - #16 (pine tree on scaffolding, close-up of man working at top, men marking and carrying planks of wood), 6/1/1983 (Box 33)
    - #17 (from new parking structure looking west toward new hospital, men working on observation room, attaching panel, pan of vent and plumbing pipes, men laying cinder blocks at base of building), 7/28/1983 (Box 33)
    - #18 (view of interior, forklift, men working, inside pan of interior rooms), 7/28/1983 (Box 33)
    - #19 (view from Huron Towers, zoom of hospital, VA Hospital/North Campus, road), 10/28/1983 (Box 33)
    - #20 (interior construction, drilling dry wall, camera walking through hallways), 12/1/1983 (Box 33)
    - #21 (cranes digging and dumping dirt), 12/9/1983 (Box 33)
    - #22 (view of Taubman foreground, hospital background, cement truck close up, men on scaffolding), 4/9/1984 (Box 33)
    - #24 (view of busy hallway in hospital, reporters photograph and interview man in wheelchair), 2/14/1986 (Box 33)
    - #163 (Hospital Dedication Reception, picketers, reception below Emergency Room Overhang, speakers), 1986 (Box 33)
    - #164 (Dedication Reception crowd in foyer), 1986 (Box 33)
    - #165 (Dedication reception beneath Emergency Room Overhang, speakers), 1986 (Box 33)
    - #166 (Dedication, speakers), 1986 (Box 33)
    - Replacement Hospital (Taubman Center) Construction (Box 33)
    - #033 (1 of 3) (Hospital Open House, people exiting bus, registration, exhibits), 10/26/1986 (Box 33)
    - #034 (2 of 3) (exhibits and displays, equipment demonstration), 10/26/1986 (Box 33)
    - #035 (3 of 3) (lines moving through building, tents with musicians), 10/26/1986 (Box 33)
    - #225 (compilation tape of hospital construction, edit log enclosed in tape), 2/4/1986 (Box 33)
    - #023 (1 of 2) (pan of complex including destroyed hospital, crane picking away at base, bulldozer), 5/26/1989 (Box 33)
    - #024 (2 of 2) (demolition, facade of hospital with middle section ripped out), 5/26/1989 (Box 33)
    - #[?] (view of demolished hospital, wrecking ball in operation), 8/7/1989 (Box 33)